MUHAMMAD MOIZ SIDDIQUI

ELECTRICAL & ELECTRONIC ENGINEER (EEE)

↑ A – 24, Farida Square, Block – 7, Gulshan – E – Iqbal, Karachi · 📞 +923330242335

moizsidd70@gmail.com · 🛅 www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddiqui ·

To work with maximum potential in a challenging and dynamic environment, with an opportunity of working with diverse group of people and enhancing my professional skills with learning and experience for career growth.

EXPERIENCE

JULY 2016 - SEP 2016

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING, BISTANIKA PVT LTD (AUTOMATION AND PROCESS SPECIALIST) MALAYSIA

- Experience in creating electrical schematic drawing using 'Draft sight' software. The task was to modify the electrical circuits of the sterilizer's control panel which is used in the industrial oil mill to operate steam, vacuum, pressure, temperature and deaerator.
- Assembled control components such as transformers, control relays, circuit breakers, drives and power supplies on the chassis panel. Gained excellent hands on and automation skills as used crimps, screws, bolts, rivets, solder, hand tools, power tools, and automation equipment.
- Experienced in the panel fabrication as built electrical layout and outsource electrical enclosures, assemblies, and controls. Successfully positioned and aligned parts exactly as it was specified in the mechanical drawings and layouts.
- Actively participated in the production inspection task to conduct functional and continuity tests of
 electrical assemblies, components, harness and plugs. Successfully accomplished the task by using
 electrical testing instruments such as ohm-meter to ensure parts and assemblies meet production
 specifications and standards.
- Built and performed Quality Assurance test by setting up different list of configurations on the online to test the complete functionality of the PLC program. Learnt about fault finding and eliminating them from the PLC program.

JUNE 2015 - OCT 2015

BRAND AMBASSADOR, DURIANA PVT LTD (SMART PHONE APPLICATION) MALAYSIA

Possess effective teamwork skills as worked with in the team to promote an online smart phone
application. My task was to educate targeted customers and promote product in various exhibition held
in different part of the city. Based on my skills and abilities, successfully helped the organization to
enhance sales.

RESEARCH AND PROJECTS

2016 - 2017

ANTI-BURGLARY SYSTEM AT ATM USING IMAGE PROCESSING (FYP)

A surveillance system developed to detect the abnormal behavior at the ATM centers and notify the location to responsible authorities in case of any possible burglary. Software's used: Python for image processing purpose and C Programming for sensors, GPS, GSM & LCD.

2017

DEVELOPMENT OF PROTOTYPE FOR EARLY WARNING FLOOD DETECTION SYSTEM

The system was developed to detect the flood and provide early warning by sending notification to the responsible authorities

2016

DEVELOPMENT OF PROTOTYPE FOR AUTO IRRIGATION SYSTEM

An embedded system used to measure the moist and temperature of the soil.

DEVELOPMENT OF SILVER JEWLERY DISPENSER VENDING MACHINE USING LABVIEW

The Program used to run the machine, should perform functions such as currency conversion, a mechanical system that simulates processes silver selection, money acceptance and product delivery, stock reporting, process monitoring and silver price updates. Technologies Involved – Simulation and programming using the LabVIEW software.

2015

FEASIBILITY STUDY FOR THE CONSTRUCTION OF POWER PLANT

A research accomplished, based on the factors and conundrums related to power plant constructions.

2014

DEVELOPMENT OF LIGHTING SCHEME FOR A HOUSE USING RELUX

Technologies Involved – Simulation and programming using the Relux software.

2014

DEVELOPMENT OF GRAFICAL USER INTERFACE FOR ANALYSIS OF DAM

Technologies Involved – Simulation and programming using the MATLAB software.

EDUCATION

AUG 2013 - OCT 2017

B. ENG (HONS) IN ELECTRICAL & ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING (2:1)

AWARDING INSTITUTE: STAFFORDSHIRE UNIVERSITY UK

Specialized Modules: Engineering Statics & Dynamics, Electrical Machines (I & II), Electrical Power Utilization, Power System Analysis, Generation, Transmission & Distribution of Electrical Power, Power Electronics & Drives, Analogue Integrated Circuits & Systems, High Voltage Engineering.

MAY 2012 - AUG 2013

FOUNDATION IN ENGINEERING (GRADE: CREDIT)

ASIA PECIFIC UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY AND INOVATION MALAYSIA.

SKILLS

Software Skills: Experience of using MATLAB, LabVIEW, Python, C programming, Multisim, LTspice, AutoCAD, PTC Creo(3.0) and excellent skills of using Microsoft Office.

Interpersonal Skills: Good Leadership, Decision Making, Teamwork, Learing and Achieving, Communication, Research and Problem Solving skills.

Instrumentation Skills: Experience of configurating Electronic Components such as Sensors, Micro computer, Micro controller, GSM shields and other electronic divices

SELECTED MEMBERSHIPS AND CERTIFICATIONS

PROJECT MANGEMENT WORKSHOP - DEC 2016

Five highly effective project leadership and team motivational techniques.

BOARD OF ENGINEERING MALAYSIA – 2013 TO 2017

REFERENCES

EXCELLENT REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST